《法外情真》前情回顾
Previously on The Guardian.
你不能再酗酒了  尼古拉斯
You can't drink any more Nicolas.
你不能再嗑药
You can't use drugs,
你也不能再
and you can not continue to lie...
对你爱的人说谎了
to the people who love you.
露露我向你求婚了
Lulu I asked you to marry me...
而你却看着我  好像我在侮辱你
and you just looked at me like I was insulting you.
这就是你和苏珊娜·佩尔上床的原因吗
So you screwed Susanne Pell?
露露求你了
Lulu please...
别走
Don't go.
尼克  你嗑了什么
Nike, what did you take?
你需要帮助
You need help.
你得做出改变了
You gonna make some changes.
我感觉我们在接下来的一个月都需要门诊治疗
My feeling is we should start outpatient for the next 30 days.
- 快点  - 我来了
- Come on! - I'm coming!
别担心  我会赶上的
Don't worry. I'll get it.
- 尼克  - 上午好  阿尔文
- Nick. - Morning, Alvin.
你知道我住哪里
You know where I live?
是的  嗯  是的
Yeah. Um, yeah.
我有段时间没见你了
I haven't seen you around for awhile.
你知道  露露  她不想让我去律所
Well, you know, Lulu-- she doesn't really want me around the clinic.
你要坐公共汽车吗
You catch the bus?
一周三天  我必须要减少燃料的使用
Three days a week. Gotta cut down on those fossil fuels.
真有你的  是啊
Good for you. Yeah.
我一直看着这些  呃  混合动力汽车
I've been looking at those, uh, hybrid cars.
也许到期限满的时候
Maybe when the lease runs.
嗯  我的公交车到了
Well, here's my bus.
- 嘿  阿尔文  你有时间可以谈一谈吗  - 我要迟到了  尼克
-Hey, Alvin, do you have a minute to talk? -I'm gonna be late, Nick.
嗯  我正在努力弥补  你知道的   那个项目
Well, I'm working on my amends for the-- you know, the program.
阿尔文  你上车吗
You coming, Alvin?
今天不了  克利姆
Not today, Clim.
嗨  诺拉
Hi, Norah.
嗨
Hi.
谢谢  谢谢
Thanks. Thanks.
谢谢你
Thank you.
第九步已经开始了  是吗
The ninth step already, huh?
我  我正在努力
l-- I'm working on it.
还挺快的
That's fast.
我写了一些东西  然后  呃
I wrote some things down, and, uh--
外面太冷了  尼克
lt's pretty cold out here, Nick.
我可以开车送你去上班  然后我们可以在车里聊一聊
I'll give you a ride to work, and we can do it in the car.
当然可以
Sure.
听着  尼克  我很欣赏你所说的一切
Look, I appreciate everything you've been saying, Nick,
当然  我很乐意过去的就让它过去  但是
and, of course, I'm happy to let bygones be bygones, but--
嗯  我已经做了三个星期了  而这只是一个30天的项目
Well, I'm three weeks in. It's only a 30-day program.
好吧  要知道  以我的情况
Well, you see, in my situation,
将近一年的时间里  我都没有做好补偿的准备
I wasn't ready to make my amends for almost a year.
好吧  阿尔文
Well, Alvin...
- 那好吧  - 对啊  对啊
- Okay, then. - Right. Right.
请进
Come in.
- 尼克  - 嘿
- Nick. - Hey.
你最近怎么样
How have you been?
还好  你好吗
Okay. How are you doing?
还可以  你收到我的留言了吗
Okay. Did you get my messages?
是的  是的  我还是觉得你应该继续
Yeah. Yeah, I still think that you should continue
接受治疗在接案子之前
with your outpatient therapy before you take cases.
- 我打电话不是为了这个  - 因为  我想  直到我知道
- I wasn't calling about that. - Because, I think, until I know
你没有喝酒或吸毒
that you're not drinking or doing drugs,
我让你在这里做律师是极不负责任的
it would be highly irresponsible for me to let you practice law here.
我打电话不是为了律所的事
I wasn't calling about the clinic.
哦
Oh.
我打电话是因为  呃
I was calling because, uh,
我想和你谈谈我做过的事
I wanted to talk to you about what I've done.
我怀了我们的孩子
About the fact that I'm pregnant with our child,
但是你却和另一个女人做爱的事儿吗
and you're having sex with another woman?
也许现在不是最好的时机
Maybe this isn't the best time.
也许不是
Maybe not.
也许  嗯  下次吧
Maybe, uh, another time.
尼克  出车祸了
Nick, it crashed.
- 是吗  - 那辆公交车  它出事了
- What? - The bus. It crashed.
- 哪一辆公交车  - 我要坐的那辆公交车  - 38号公交车
- What bus? - My bus-- the 38B.
冲出了51号公路上的护栏
Went over a guardrail on Route 51 .
新闻报道说  很多人都死了
The news is saying that a lot of people are dead.
我本来是要上车的
I was just about to get on it.
我本来应该在那辆公共汽车上
I was supposed to be on that bus.
第三季  第十三集
法外真情
翻译   不会吐泡泡   的金鱼
校对  油 球
特效  转轮 枪
- 这事儿我们得抢占先机  呃  派特  - 很好
- We'll stay ahead of this, uh, Pat. - Good.
杰克已经在协调公关了
Jake is already coordinating with the-- your PR--
我们今天要制定悲伤咨询计划
We're setting up a grief counseling plan today.
好的
Good.
- 现在将会有民事诉讼出现
- Now, there will be civil suits filed.
当然  我们的答案是全面否定所有索赔和责任
Our answer, of course, will be a blanket denial of all claims and liability.
司机给警察提供了血液和尿液样本
The driver's given blood and urine samples to the police,
他现在和他的女儿一起在县医院
and he's down at the county hospital right now with his daughter,
但是  呃  他已经同意今天晚些时候和我们谈谈
but, uh, he has agreed to speak with us later today.
我会去采访那个司机
I'll interview the driver.
不  杰克会处理的
No. Jake's taking care of that.
我可以采访的
I can do it.
请注意  它不会是
Be advised. It won't be a--
不  让杰克来处理
No. Jake's on that.
但是我们确实需要  呃  公共汽车上的维修记录
But we do need, uh, maintenance records on the bus,
还有司机的驾驶手册
and, uh, the regulation manual for your drivers.
悲惨的阿勒格尼县过境公交车事故
...tragic AIlegheny County Transit bus crash
在5号公路已经有5人死亡
on Route 5S has reached S5.
死亡人数正在攀升
The death toll has climbed...
好吧  让我们开始工作吧
Well, let's get to work.
我稍后再和你谈  好吗？
I'll talk to you later, okay?
我可以和司机去交涉
I can talk to the driver.
我想也许你可以顺便去一下交通部门
I thought maybe you could, uh, drop over to the Transit Authority
检查一下事故重建工作
and check on that accident reconstruction work.
好吧  我可以在去司机家的路上这么做
Well, I could do that on the way to the driver's house.
尼古拉斯  这个案子可能会让阿勒格尼损失数千万美元
Nicholas, this case could cost Allegheny Transit tens of millions of dollars.
他们需要我们保持连贯性和一致性
What they need from us is continuity and consistency.
你是说  这案子我不能插手吗
You're saying I can't work on it?
好吧  跟我进来一下
Well, come on in here a minute.
尼古拉斯  你现在有很多其他的事情要处理
Nicholas, you've got a lot of important stuff going on right now for yourself--
我必须得工作
I gotta work.
好吧
Right.
- 爸爸  我能应付的  - 好吧
- Dad, I can handle working. - All right.
在去司机家的路上  我会到交通局去
I will stop by the Transit Authority on the way to the driver's house.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
请进
Come in.
怎么了
What is it?
我有一个新的委托人  他只有13岁
I got a new client. He's 13,
他的父亲在今天的公交车事故里去世了
and his father died today in that bus accident.
嗯
Uh-huh.
他叫康纳·亚当斯  他也在公共汽车上
His name is Connor Adams. He was on the bus, too.
他受伤了吗
Was he hurt?
他的手腕受伤了  他缝了几针  但除此之外
His wrist. He's got some stitches, but otherwise--
嗯  我能为你做些什么
Well, what can I do for you?
康纳和他的父亲独自居住  他母亲几年前去世了
Connor and his father lived alone. The mother died a few years ago.
这里唯一的亲戚是他的一位堂兄和叔叔
The only relatives in the area are a cousin and an uncle.
我做了一些背景调查  事实证明
I did a little background check, and it turns out that--
呃  你能直接告诉我吗  苏珊娜
Uh, could you just tell me, Suzanne?
好吧  好的
Right. Okay.
康纳的叔叔菲尔在州立监狱呆了七年
Um, Connor's Uncle Phil spent seven years in a state prison
因为故意伤害和强奸
for aggravated assault and rape.
他还酗酒  而且他的公寓
He's still drinking heavily, and his apartment--
嗯  那他的堂兄呢
Well, what about the cousin?
康纳现在和他在一起  戴尔的问题是
Connor's with him now. The problem with Cousin Dell
他曾经很严重地忽视过自己的孩子
is that, uh, he already has a severe history of neglect with his own kids.
好的
Okay.
所以我们今天必须把康纳从监护那儿带走
So we're gonna have to go in and take Connor out of his custody today.
然后我想到了你
And I thought of you,
因为  嗯  他需要的是一个真正能代表他的人
because, well, he just needs someone really good to represent him,
如果你不介意和我一起工作的话
if you don't mind working with me.
好吧  让我们不要把这件事牵扯到我们身上  苏珊娜
Well, let's not make this about us, Suzanne.
我今天午饭  请全体员工吃饭
I'm taking the entire staff out to lunch-- On me.
- 你想要过来吗  - 哦 不了  谢谢你  阿尔文
- You guys want to come? - Oh, no, thank you, Alvin.
苏珊娜
Suzanne?
哦  这很好  但是不  谢谢你
Oh, nice, but no, thank you.
好吧
Okay.
那么  我现在就去安排会议
So, I'll just go ahead and set up that meeting.
好的
Yeah.
康纳  我知道这对你来说是很艰难
So, Connor, I know this is a very hard time for you,
我非常感谢你今天可以过来和我们谈话
and I really appreciate you coming and talking today.
我们能得到多少
How much do we get?
嗯 呃  不好意思
Uh, uh, excuse me?
我们能得到多少
How much do we get?
- 是的  亚当斯先生  呃  - 戴尔
- Yeah, Mr. Adams, uh-- - Dell.
戴尔  戴尔  我们来这里不是为了谈论钱
Dell. Dell, we're not here to discuss money.
我们来这里讨论公交车上发生的事情
We're here to discuss what happened on the bus.
- 您代表公交车公司  - 对的
- You represent the bus company? - Right.
康纳说  司机故意撞毁了公交车
Connor said the driver crashed the bus on purpose.
所以  我们可以得到多少
So, how much do we get?
亚当斯先生吗   尼克·法林  很高兴认识你
Mr. Adams? Nick Fallin. Nice to meet you.
康纳  是吗
Connor, right?
康纳  你说公交车司机故意撞坏公交车的
Connor, you said the bus driver crashed the bus on purpose?
是的
Yeah.
- 你告诉警察了吗  - 没有
- Did you tell that to the police? - No.
康纳  如果他们不付钱  跟你就没得谈
Connor, if they're not paying, you're not talking.
詹金斯先生  很抱歉打扰你
Mr. Jenkins, I'm sorry to disturb you.
- 你为ACT工作  - 是的
- You work for ACT? - That's right.
我今天需要和你谈谈这次事故
I need to speak with you about this accident today.
现在  我知道你们都记得那一天
[Man on TV] Now, J know you all remember that day.
诺拉  你和你奶奶到另一个房间去好吗
Norah, would you go into the other room with your grandma, please?
从西奈山下来
...come down Mount Sinai...
我已经把一切都告诉了警察
Already told the police everything.
- 是的  - 甚至是尿检  抽血
- Right. - Even pissed in a cup, gave blood,
对着酒精测醉仪吹气
blew into a breathalyzer.
他们说  一切都没问题
All came back fine, they said.
如果可以的话  我得把它录下来
I have to record this, if it's okay.
谢谢你
Thank you.
请说出你的名字和工作地点
Uh, please state your name and where you work.
克利姆·詹金斯  我是城市线的公共汽车司机
Clim Jenkins. I'm a bus driver for the city lines.
詹金斯先生  你开的是38号公交车
Mr. Jenkins, you were driving the 38B bus
在今天发生了车祸
that was involved in the accident today?
是的
Yes.
我采访了另一个在那辆公交车上的人
I interviewed someone else that was actually on that bus--
一个坐在前排的男孩
a boy that was sitting up at the front.
好的
Okay.
他把车祸归咎于你
He blames you for the accident.
他说你故意撞了公交车
He said that you crashed the bus intentionally.
我决不会故意撞公共汽车的
I would never crash the bus intentionally.
当然不会  我很抱歉
Of course not. I'm sorry.
詹金斯先生  你能  你能告诉我对于车祸你还记得什么吗
Mr. Jenkins, can you-- can you tell me what you remember of the crash?
你在51号公路上开车
You were driving on Route 51 .
你开得有多快
How fast were you going?
嗯  35码  也许40码
Um, 35, maybe 40.
然后发生了什么事
Then what happened?
我看到了下一站
I saw the next stop up ahead.
接下来我知道的是  公共汽车打滑了
The next thing I know, the-- the bus was skidding.
我觉得我一定是在冰面上开车
I must've driven over a patch of ice.
你不会想到要踩刹车的
You don't want to hit the brakes
因为  你知道的  车失去控制了
because, you know, you lose control,
所以  我  我只是想  呃  呃  开过去
so, l-- I just tried to, uh, uh, steer through it.
我看见  嗯
I saw, uh,
护栏
the guardrail coming up,
然后 嗯
and, uh,
当时我猛踩刹车
that's when I slammed on the brakes,
但是 呃
but, uh...
它没有停下来
it just kept going.
嘿  苏珊娜
Hey, Suzanne.
你在这里做什么
What are you doing here?
我有一个为期30天的项目  它有12个步骤
lt's a 30-day program, and it has 12 steps,
其中一个步骤是
and one of the steps
嗯  是列一个名单
is to, uh, make a list of people
你可能伤害过的人的名单
that you may have either hurt
或者虐待过的人  然后做出补偿
or-- or mistreated and then make amends.
好的
Okay.
你  你在我的名单上
You're-- You're on my list.
为什么
Why?
呃  当我喝醉的时候  我和你上床了
Uh, when l-- when I had the problem drinking, l-- I slept with you.
我喜欢和你睡觉  尼克
I enjoyed sleeping with you, Nick.
我的意思是
I guess what I mean is
这对我来说只是性
it was just sex to me.
你为做爱而道歉吗
Are you apologizing for having sex?
- 你不喜欢和我做爱吗  - 不  是的  我  我喜欢
- Didn't you enjoy having sex with me? - No. Yeah, l-- I did.
我只是  我  我  我在为我的不认真道歉
I just-- I'm-- I'm-- I'm apologizing for not taking it more seriously.
哦
Oh.
嗯  我喜欢过你
Oh, um, I liked you.
我知道  这就是我道歉的原因
I know. That's-- That's why I'm apologizing.
我不明白你为什么要道歉
I don't understand what you're apologizing for.
我告诉过你
I told you.
你告诉我你没有认真对待我
You told me that you didn't take me seriously--
你把我当婊子一样对待
that you kind of treated me like a whore,
但是你没有告诉我为什么
but you didn't tell me why.
对不起  我不接受你的道歉
I'm sorry, but I don't accept that apology.
哦  嘿  呃  帕特·哈格蒂
Oh, hey. Uh, Pat Hagerty
阿勒格尼的人会在10点来这里
and the guys from ACT are gonna be here at 10:OO.
- 对  - 你  呃  跟司机谈过了
- Right. - And you, uh, spoke to the driver.
- 对的  - 怎么样
- Right. - How'd it go?
他的说法很简单明了
His account seemed straight forward.
嗯  我的意思是  路上有黑冰
Well, I mean, there's black ice on the road,
那个孩子说的还没得到证实
and that kid's story hasn't been corroborated
被其他目击者证实吗
by any of the other witnesses?
- 对  - 对的
- Right. - Right.
哦
Oh.
这是什么
What's this?
如你所知  我参加了一个为期30天的项目
As you know, I'm in a 30-day program.
- 好的  - 我正在努力弥补
- Right. - I'm working on making my amends
那些我有意无意伤害过的人
with people I may have hurt advertently or inadvertently.
对啊
Right.
嗯  是要我现在看吗
Uh, should I read it now?
或者晚些时候
Or later.
好
Right.
所以  我检查了克利姆的工作记录  没有发生过意外
So, l-- I reviewed Clims work records, and there's no prior accidents.
我的意思是  在十多年的服务期间  没有人对他投诉过
I mean, not a single complaint against him in over ten years of service.
是啊  我没有在信中写
Yeah, I didn't write in the letter
我从你那拿走了斯卡拉化学制品的单子
that I took Sklar Chemical from you.
我无意中听到你说他们有意向
I overheard you talking about how they were in play,
然后我开了个会  但是没邀请你
and I set up a meeting and I didn't invite you.
哦
Oh.
美国国家运输安全委员会有没有就调查与你联系过
Did the NTSB contact you about their investigation?
因为他们真的很讨厌
Because they can be a real pain in the ass.
等一等  你背着我去了斯卡拉化学公司
Wait. You went behind my back to Sklar Chemical?
是啊
Yeah.
你以前也这样做过吗
Have you done this other times as well?
嘿
Hey.
好吧  黑冰可以救ACT的案子
Well, that black ice situation's gonna save ACT's ass.
- 是啊  - 那个司机如何
- Yeah. - What about that driver?
你认为他在说谎吗
You think he's being truthful?
是的
Yes, I do.
好吧
Good.
爸爸  我  呃
Dad, l, uh...
我想给杰克我在斯克拉化学公司的客户提成
I want to give Jake my source credit for Sklar Chemical.
什么  你是什么意思
Wh-- What do you mean?
嗯  还有麦肯齐航运公司
Uh, and also MacKenzie Shipping
约翰逊科技公司
and Johnson Technology.
你还好吗  孩子
Are you okay, son?
是的
Yeah.
我做过一些事情  嗯
There's some things that-- that I've done that, uh,
对此我很抱歉
I'm sorry for.
我对你撒了谎  我不太可靠  而且
I've lied to you, and I've been unreliable and--
我把一些事情归咎于你
and I've blamed you for some things that--
你可能都没有做的事情
that you probably didn't do.
怎么了  孩子
What the hell, son?
哦  请看一下
Oh, just read it, please.
这是道歉
lt's an apology.
只要我们道歉  我
As long as we're apologizing, l--
我想说对不起
I'd like to say I'm sorry.
为了什么
What for?
对于我所做的一切
Whatever the hell I've done.
哦
Oh.
好吧  帕特·哈格蒂在这里
Well, Pat Hagerty's here.
我们最好给他做一个简报
We better give him a briefing.
康纳
Connor?
你好  我是路易莎·阿切尔
Hi, I'm Louisa Archer.
我会成为你的律师  你想和我一起去吗
I'll be your lawyer. You want to come with me?
收容所怎么样
How's the shelter?
它糟透了
It sucks.
我不明白为什么我不能和戴尔在一起
I don't understand why I couldn't just stay with Dell.
在这里
ln here.
好吧  你的  呃  你的社工  苏珊娜
Well, your, uh-- your social worker, Suzanne--
她  她  嗯
she-- she, um--
她为你找到了一个很好的寄养家庭
she found a-- a-- a nice foster family for you
在你家附近  所以你可以留在你的学校
that's in your neighborhood so you can stay in your school.
而且  呃  他们实际上有另一个养子
And, uh, they actually have another foster child.
他的名字是杰里米  他和你年纪相当
His name's Jeremy. He's about your age.
所以呢
So?
所以  我们现在要去法院了
So, we're gonna go to court now,
我们要作出正式安置决定
and we're gonna make the placement official.
快一点  我们要迟到了
Come on. We're gonna be late.
嘿  等一等我
Hey, wait for me.
- 再见  - 再见  小卡
- See you later. - Bye, Cam.
嘿  我是尼克
Hey, uh, my name is Nick.
我知道你是谁
I know who you are.
你是苏珊娜的儿子  对吧
You're Suzanne's son, right?
是的  小卡
Yeah. Cam.
是的  嗯  你知道你妈妈在家吗
Right. Um, do you know if your mom's home?
她今天很早就去上班了
Uh, she left for work early today.
好吧  今天不上学吗
Okay. No school today?
下雪了  我会告诉她你来过的
Snow day. I'll tell her you stopped by.
好的
All right.
呃  小卡  呃
Uh, Cam, um,
昨晚  当我和你妈妈说话的时候
last night, when I was talking to your mom, uh...
你伤了我妈妈的心  她哭了快一个小时
You hurt my mom's feelings pretty bad. She cried for, like, an hour.
是啊
Right.
好吧  如果昨晚我做了什么让你不高兴的事
Well, if last night, l-- I did anything that upset you,
我只是想让你知道
I just want you to know that, you know,
如果有什么我能做的  呃
if there's anything that I can do, uh...
或是知道我很抱歉
Or just know I'm sorry.
好的
Okay, man.
你知道  因为你要生活和希顿一家人生活
You know, just because you're going to live with the Heatons
这并不意味着我们以后不帮你了
doesn't mean that we still won't help you.
我们会每个月来看你一次
We're gonna come visit you once a month,
如果你需要什么  我们会帮你的  好吗
and if there are things that you need, we'll help you get them, okay?
哦  她来了
Oh, here she is.
你好
Hi.
康纳  这是希顿先生和夫人
Connor, this is Mr. and Mrs. Heaton.
这是康纳
This is Connor.
佩尔小姐
Miss Pell.
希顿夫妇成为养父母已经超过五年了
The Heatons have been foster parents for over five years.
他们和另外三个孩子相处得非常好
They've done a remarkably good job with their three other children.
好的  阿切尔小姐吗
Okay. Miss Archer?
我觉得这个安排很好
I think it's a terrific placement.
康纳  你觉得怎么样
Connor, how do you feel about this?
我不跟黑鬼住在一起
I ain't living with a nigger.
- 他的父亲刚刚去世  - 我知道
- His father just died. - I know that.
他  他只是经历了一段非常艰难的时期  他想和他的家人在一起
He-- He's just having a really hard time, and he wants to be with his family.
好吧  好吧
Right. Well,
很明显我们不能让康纳和希顿夫妇住在一起
obviously we cannot place Connor with the Heatons.
对
Right.
但是  达姆森法官  我是说  考虑到他的
But, also, Judge Damsen, I mean, given his, uh--
考虑他的什么  阿切尔小姐
His what, Miss Archer?
他的情绪
His mood.
呃  把他留在集体收容所里  呃
Uh, keeping him in a group shelter with, uh--
和黑人孩子在一起
With black kids?
这可能不会很好
It might not work out so well.
他还是会在阿勒格尼男孩之家
He'll remain at the Allegheny Boys Home.
我将安排心理咨询和治疗
I will order counseling and therapy.
谢谢你  女士
Thank you, ladies.
好吧  我可能找不到
Okay, well, I won't be able to find
一个适合康纳的家庭
a group home for Connor without minority kids.
嗯  我相信你会尽力的
Well, I'm sure you'll do your best.
嘿  嘿
Hey. Hey.
我已经向你道歉了  露露
I've apologized to you, Lulu.
是吗
Right?
我希望停止这一切
I would like for this to stop.
什么
What?
他从没告诉我你怀孕了
He never told me that you were pregnant.
- 你知道我和他住在一起  - 我知道  他也是
- You knew I was living with him. - I did. So did he.
好吧  我绝对不会做那种事
Well, I just would never do something like that.
我不是那样的人  露露  我  我是一个母亲
I'm not like that. Lulu, l-- I'm a mom.
如果我知道你怀孕了
lf I'd known that you were pregnant--
我不明白你的意思  你知道我们住在一起
You know, I don't understand you. You knew that we were living together.
我怀孕了  这有什么关系
The fact that I'm pregnant-- why does that make a difference?
有关系  我是说  我以为他喜欢我
It does. I mean, l-- I thought he liked me.
我以为我有机会
I thought I had a chance.
你好  她还没有回来
Hey, man. She's still not here.
好吧
Okay.
- 我会告诉她你在找她  - 好的
- I'll tell her you're looking for her. - All right.
哦  嘿
Oh. Hey.
我在想你之前说的话
I was thinking about what you said earlier.
对
Right.
如果可以  你说你能为我做点什么
About if there was anything you could do for me.
是的
Yeah?
它里面有颗珍珠
It had a pearl in it.
所以
So?
这是我爸爸给她的
My dad gave it to her,
情人节就要到了
and Valentine's Day is coming up,
我想把它给我妈妈
and I wanted to give it to my mom,
但我没有钱修理它或买颗新珍珠
but I don't have the money to fix it or buy a new pearl.
你明白吗
You know?
是的
Yeah.
所以你说如果你能做点什么
So, you said if there was anything you could do...
- 嗨  - 你一个人吗
- Hey. - You alone?
- 是的  - 披萨可能凉了
- I was. - Pizza's probably cold.
我会把它放进烤箱里的
I'll put it in the oven.
我已经两天没睡觉了
I have not slept for two days.
睡不着  没有办法睡着
Can't sleep. Cannot sleep.
- 你救了我的命
- You may have saved my life.
我越想越觉得你是个天使
The more I think about it, you were, like-- I don't know-- an angel.
阿尔文  求你了  就
Hey, Alvin, please, just...
你想来点咖啡吗
You want some comee?
当然
Sure.
我想露露可能需要一些帮助  嗯  考虑到你的特殊性
You know, I think Lulu may need some help, uh, understanding your particularities.
例如  她的父亲  我看见那个人了  对吧
For instance, her father. I saw that guy, right?
他酗酒成性
Had alcoholic written all over him.
很明显 她是看着一个瘾君子长大的
Clearly she grew up watching somebody enable an addict.
- 明白我的意思吗  - 没有
- Know what I mean? - No.
这个孩子的父亲在车祸中丧生
So, this kid whose dad died in the crash,
今天在法庭上  在达姆森法官面前
in court today, in front of Judge Damsen--
苏珊娜和露露给他找了寄养家庭
Suzanne and Lulu bring in this foster family.
父亲是白人  母亲是黑人
Dad's white, mom's black.
这个孩子  在法庭前  说了那个单词
This kid, in front of the court, says the N word.
拒绝去寄养家庭
Refuses to go with the foster family.
他全家都是白人至上主义者
His whole family's, like, these white supremacists.
他父亲去世了很难过  但是  嗯  伙计
Sad story about the dad dying, but, uh, man.
我也认识他的父亲
I knew the father, too,
从公交车上
from the bus.
从没见过那个孩子  但是
Never saw the kid, but, uh,
他父亲以前叫那个司机的名字时
the dad used to call that, uh, driver names
总是很小声
all the time, under his breath.
那个司机  克利姆 是个好人
The driver, Clim-- good man--
他总是直直地盯着前方  开着公交车
just used to stare straight ahead and drive that bus.
- 嘿  - 嗨
- Hey. - Hi.
- 你爸爸在吗  - 没有  只有奶奶在家
- Is your daddy here? - No. Just Grandma.
好的
All right.
是诺拉  对吧
lt's-- It's Norah, right?
我是尼克  我昨天来过
I'm Nick. l-- I came around yesterday.
我听说  呃  公车上可能有人不太友好
I heard that there, uh, might've been someone on the bus that wasn't very nice.
是的
Yeah.
我想知道你是否记得
I was wondering if you remember
如果你爸爸有和其他人相处得不好
if your dad was having a-- a bad time with anyone.
也许不是昨天  也许  也许  也许是另一天
Maybe not yesterday, maybe-- maybe-- maybe another day?
有时候  有个男人会对爸爸说些事情
This man, some days, would say things to Daddy.
什么样的事情
What kind of things?
辱骂他
Call him bad names.
好的
Okay.
爸爸总是告诉我不要听
Daddy always told me not to listen.
他说那种话不应该听
He said that kind of stum shouldn't be listened to.
哦  这是对的  你爸爸是对的
Oh, that's right. Your daddy's right.
这个人对你爸爸很刻薄
This man that was mean to your daddy,
车撞毁的时候他在车上吗
was-- was he on the bus when it crashed?
好的  谢谢你  诺拉
Okay. Thanks, Norah.
他儿子叫我黑鬼
His son called me a nigger.
他什么时候说的
When did he do that?
在车撞毁之前
Before we crashed.
爸爸转过身来
Daddy turned around.
他真的很生气
He was really mad.
他转过身来  对着那个孩子和爸爸大喊
He turned around and yelled at the kid and his dad,
事情就是这样发生的
and that's when it happened.
那么  露露  我想事情就这样了
So, I think that's everything.
我回头再跟你说  好吧  再见  亲爱的
I'll talk to you about it later. Okay. Bye, sweetie.
哦  发生了什么事
Oh. What happened?
康纳和其他孩子相处得不太好
Connor's not exactly getting along with the other kids.
Come on.
好吧  坐下来  康纳
Okay, have a seat, Connor.
你想告诉我发生了什么事吗
You want to tell me what's going on?
You want to tell me what happened?
康纳
Connor?
我知道这对你来说一定是非常困难的时刻
You know, I know this must be an extremely difficult time for you--
我爸爸的葬礼在星期五
My dad's funeral is on Friday.
好吧  我知道你一定很爱你爸爸
All right. You know, I know that you must have loved your dad a lot--
- 别谈论我的父亲  - 不，我只是说
- Don't talk about my father. - No, I just mean--
不要谈论我的父亲
Don't talk about him.
如果坚信你父亲相信的东西
lf you keep believing the things that your father believed
也继续这样行事  你就会失去一切的
and you keep acting the way that you act, you're gonna lose everything.
你会失去每一个出现在你面前的机会的
You will lose every opportunity that comes your way.
没人会想要你的  康纳
No one will want you, Connor.
对不起
I'm sorry.
没有人会的
Nobody will.
我知道你昨晚来过我家
Understand you stopped by the house last night.
你和诺拉谈过了
Understand you spoke to Norah.
她告诉你的是真的
What she told you was true.
是真的  我当时没看路
lt's true. I wasn't looking.
嗯  坐下来
Um, sit down.
你好
Hi.
呃  克利姆  呃  你前几天说过  嗯
Uh, Clim, uh, you said the other day that, uh,
如果你在冰上行驶时踩刹车
if you'd hit the brakes when you were going over the ice
你仍然会失去对公交车的控制
that you still would have lost control of the bus.
对的
Right.
你说过你没有超速
You said that you weren't exceeding the speed limit.
对
Right.
你也没有鲁莽驾驶
And you weren't driving recklessly.
对的
Right.
再给你一次机会你会改变什么
Would you have done anything differently?
我把目光从路上移开
I looked away from the road.
我转向那个人  对他大喊
I turned to the man, and I yelled at him.
克利姆  如果你把这次事故归咎于自己
Clim, if-- if you blame yourself for this accident,
公交车公司会和你撇清关系的
the bus company will distance itself from you.
过失杀人罪可能会受到刑事指控
There may be criminal charges filed for negligent homicide.
你明白这是什么意思吗
You understand what that means?
我是说  这可能是个意外
I mean, this could have been an accident.
这不一定是你的错
It doesn't have to be your fault.
让我们说一点不一样的
Let's say I say things different.
这对诺拉意味着什么
What does that mean for Norah?
我说我没有看别处
I say I didn't look away.
她不得不说同样的话  对吧
She has to say the same thing, right?
对吗
Right?
这个人  几个月前
This guy, a few months ago,
上了公交车  但是他没有车费
gets on the bus, and he don't have the fare.
我告诉他  他得付钱才能乘车
I tell him he gotta pay to ride.
他叫我放过他一次  因为我以前也见过他
He tells me to give him a break because I seen him before.
我告诉他我不能那样做
I tell him I can't do that.
所以他叫我
So he calls me--
他叫我黑鬼
he calls me a nigger,
然后下车了
and he gets off the bus.
第二天早上  他上了车
The next morning, he gets on,
他就坐在我后面
and he sits down right behind me,
然后开始骂我
and he starts with the names,
从卡内基一直到纽约一直说
and he keeps it up all the way from Carnegie into the city.
而我只能听他说
And I just listen to him.
试着想象他不在那里
Try to imagine that he's not there.
做好我的本职工作
Just do my job.
事发当天
Day it happened--
有暴风雪
snowstorm.
所有的学校都不上课
All the schools were closed.
因此  我让我的女儿诺拉和我一起乘车
I had my daughter, Norah, riding with me on account of that.
这个男人和他的儿子上了公共汽车
This man gets on the bus with his boy.
他们就坐在我旁边
They sit down close to me.
我听见他在窃窃私语
I hear him whispering.
他开始跟我说话
He started saying things to me
当着他儿子的面  当着我女儿的面
in front of his boy, in front of my daughter.
我看了看我的女儿  她在盯着地板看
I look at my daughter. She's staring at the floor.
我在考虑是否要停车
I try to think whether to stop the bus or not.
我  我想还是不了
l-- I think no.
我们在山上行驶
So, we drive over the hill, right?
就在这时  我听到
And that's when I hear it--
他的儿子
his boy
叫我的宝贝
calling my baby
黑鬼
a nigger.
叫我的宝贝那个词
Calling my baby that word.
我转向那个人和他的孩子
I turned to that man and his child
把我要对他说的话告诉了他
and I tell him what I tell him,
接下来
and the next thing I know,
公交车
the bus...
接下来我知道的是
The next thing I know...
你知道
You see,
我没有做好我的本职工作
I turned away from my job.
我没有做好
I turned away.
- 这是个问题   - 对啊
- Well, this is a problem. - Right.
你应该立即让他停职  把它公布于众
You should suspend him immediately. Make that public.
这只是个开始  让你和他在媒体下保持距离
lt's just a start to distancing yourself from him in the press.
好的
Okay.
同意与地方检察官办公室通力合作
Agree to cooperate fully with the D.A# s office
以防他们决定起诉
in case they decide to press charges.
好的
Right.
现在  主动权肯定在我们这边
Now, this is gonna come back at us for sure.
所以  我找到了一个愿意收养康纳的家庭
So, found a family that will consider taking Connor.
就像你说的  我告诉了他们康纳的情绪
I told them about his mood, as you said,
而且  嗯  他们似乎可以胜任这个任务
and, um, they seem to be up to the task.
好的
Okay.
那么我会把会议安排在明天早上
So I'm scheduling a meeting for tomorrow morning.
我想你可能想去那儿
Thought you might want to be there.
好的
Okay.
阿尔文  你有空吗
Uh, Alvin, do you have a second?
嗯  共同家属匿名协会
Uh, Co-Dependents Anonymous?
是的
Right.
对的  还有匿名戒酒者协会
Right. And Al-Anon.
其中一个可能适合你
One of them might be right for you.
这有点无礼
lt's kind of offensive.
我不是故意要冒犯你的
Well, I didn't mean to offend you.
- 不  这意味着我是那个拥有  - 50%
-No, it implies that I'm the one who has-- -Fifty percent.
什么
What?
你和任何人都有50%的关系
You are 50 percent of any relationship.
好吧  好的  谢谢你  阿尔文  非常感谢
Well, okay. Thank you, Alvin, very much.
好好考虑一下
Just think about it.
谢谢你  非常感谢
Thank you. Thanks a lot.
嘿
Hey.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry
开始了一件我没想完成的事情
for starting something that I didn't intend to finish.
我向你隐瞒了一些信息
I withheld certain information from you.
如果我问你露露的事  你会告诉我真相吗
lf I'd asked you about Lulu, would you have told me the truth?
我想不会
I don't think so.
也许这就是你要道歉的地方
Well, maybe that's what you're sorry for.
或许吧
Maybe.
或许
你拿到了吗
Did you get it?
我原谅你了  伙计
I forgive you, man.
谢谢你抽出时间来
Thank you for your time.
这不是我的错
lt's not my fault.
如果他们不喜欢我  那不是我的错
lf they don't like me, it's not my fault.
康纳  你得跟约翰逊先生走了
Connor, you're gonna have to go with Mr. Johnson now.
嗯  我想他们不能胜任这项工作  是吧
Well, I guess they weren't up to the task, huh?
寄养夫妇吗
The foster couple?
这是一个保守的说法
That's an understatement.
他在那次采访中使用了多少次“黑鬼”这个词
How many times did he use the word ''darkie'' in that interview?
六次
I counted six.
其他的呢  我是说  太不可思议了
And the other words? I mean, it was amazing.
几乎是
It was almost...
我不知道  我不知道那是什么感觉
I don't know. I don't know what that was like.
是啊
Yeah.
或许还是有家庭可以收养他的
Maybe there's a family out there for him
一旦他得到心理咨询和治疗
once he gets counseling and therapy.
他不会改变的
He won't change.
不会吧
No.
对他来说事情的发展就可能不会那么顺利
Things probably aren't going to go so well for him.
那是保守的说法
That's an understatement.
我不知道你有个儿子
Uh, I didn't know that you had a son.
是的  他叫小卡
Yeah. His name's Cam.
小卡  他几岁了
Cam. How old is he?
十岁了
He's ten.
我不知道
I didn't know that.
你应该找个时间见见他
You should meet him sometime.
- 如果我要去监狱  - 克利姆  你不会去监狱的
- If I gotta go to jail-- - Clim, you're not gonna go to jail.
我不知道谁会来照顾我的女儿和母亲
I don't know who's gonna look after my daughter and my mother.
你需要做的是尽快找个律师
What you need to do is get yourself a lawyer as soon as you can.
- 如果你找不到  - 那样就好了
- If you can't amord one-- - Right.
我会有公共辩护人的
I'll get one of those public defender men.
好吧  除非提交刑事诉讼
Well, only if criminal charges are filed.
是现在你需要找一位能够代表你的律师
But right now you need to find a lawyer that'll represent you civilly.
给那个号码打个电话  去找路易莎·阿切尔
Give that number a call. Ask for Louisa Archer.
她会帮助你的
She'll help get you started.
对于像你这样的人来说  免费律师跟你打交道没什么赢的机会
Probably don't stand much of a chance with a free lawyer against guys like you.
爸爸
Daddy?
现在不行  甜心
Not now, sweetheart.
奶奶有点事  我想她需要你
There's something with Grandma. I think she needs you.
嗯  好的
Mmm, okay.
克利姆  祝你好运
Clim, good luck.
谢谢
Thanks.
儿子  我呼吸很困难
Son, I'm having a hard time with my breathing.
- 嗨  - 嗨
- Hi. - Hi.
外面太冷了
lt's freezing out here.
哦
Oh.
那是什么
What's that?
打开它
Just open it.
是什么
What is it?
这是项目的证书
lt's a certificate from the program.
- 一个证书吗  - 是的  我毕业了
- A certificate? - Yeah. I graduated.
哦  我明白了  已经30天了
Oh, I see. It's been 30 days.
对的
Right.
好吧  祝贺你完成了你的项目
Well, congratulations on completing your program.
谢谢你
Thank you.
露露  我在想我们的事
You know, Lulu, I was wondering about us.
- 我们怎么了  - 如果我们能试一试
- What about us? - If we could try to just--
- 试一试  - 是的 尝试一下
- Try? - Right. Try.
不
No.
露露
Lulu...
不
No.
只是试一试
Just try.
- 因为你有了证书  - 不只是这样
- Because you have a certificate? - Well, not just that.
- 那只是一张纸  尼克  是的
- That's just a piece of paper, Nick. - Right.
而且才过了30天
And it's only been 30 days.
唷  风太大了
Whew. That wind is really something.
你拿到了证书
You have your certificate.
嗯  是啊  是啊
Uh, yeah. Yeah.
祝贺你
Congratulations.
我可以坐下吗
Mind if I sit?
三十天了  这是一种进步
Thirty days. That's progress.
进步
Progress.
你做的事太惊人了
lt's amazing what you did--
在如此短的时间内完成所有这些步骤
finishing all those steps in so short a time.
你知道  阿尔文  跟你说实话
You know, Alvin, to be honest with you--
尼克  我以前也经历过这种事
Nick, I've been through this before.
这个   这个加速的事情
And this-- this acceleration thing--
是吗
Yeah?
是废话
ls crap.
- 废话  - 废话
- Crap. - Crap.
因为你只是
Because you just--
你得正视你的问题  尼克
You have to surrender to the problem, Nick.
至少你承认有这个问题
At least admit you have one.
- 阿尔文，你知道吗  是吗
- Alvin, you know what? - Yeah?
我没有  我没有拯救你的生命
I didn't-- I didn't save your life.
- 好吧  - 所以
- Okay. - So--
所以你可以不用再来了
So you can stop coming around here.
这些事  我走出来了  尼克
I've recovered before, Nick.
- 这就是我想说的  - 是的
- That's all I'm saying. - Yeah.
这是你余生都应该要做的事
lt's something you do for the rest of your life.
这不是你可以加速的
lt's not something you can speed up,
除非你想让你的余生  呃
unless you want the rest of your life to, uh--
我不知道  过得更快
I don't know-- go faster
或者干脆消失
or just go away.
嘿  你准备好了吗
Hey. You ready?
在葬礼后 收容所的那个女人
Uh, after the funeral, the woman from the shelter here
带你去你表弟家参加招待会  好吗
is gonna take you to your cousin's for the reception, okay?
你过得如何
How you doing?
我不喜欢这里
I don't like it here.
我知道
I know.
我很抱歉  康纳
I'm sorry, Connor.
我只想回家
I just want to go home.
我只想要我爸爸
I just want my dad.
走吧
Come on.
请进
Come in.
我很抱歉  我打扰到你们了吗
I'm sorry. Um, am I interrupting something?
不  我正要走  我待会再跟你说
Nope. I was just leaving. I'll talk to you later.
你今天早上给我打电话了
You called this morning?
是的  请坐
Yeah. Have a seat.
我觉得你可以重新开始接案子了
I think it's okay for you to start taking cases again.
好的
Good.
好吧  嗯  有个人
Right. So, uh, there's a man.
他叫阿尔弗雷德·金斯顿
His name is Alfred Kingston.
嗯  他被误判了强奸罪
Um, he was wrongfully convicted of rape,
他被判了十年监禁
and he served ten years of a hundred-year sentence
在DNA测试证明他无罪之前
before the DNA test cleared him of the charges.
好的
Okay.
他想要儿子的监护权  但问题在于他的妻子
He wants custody of his son, but the problem is the wife.
她有点激动  而阿尔弗雷德在想他怎么才能要回他的孩子
She's kind of moved on, and Alfred's just wondering how he's gonna get his kid back.
好吧  明白了  谢谢你
Okay. Got it. Thank you.
他在外面等你
He's waiting for you outside.
金斯顿先生  尼克·福林
Mr. Kingston? Nick Fallin.
- 我知道你是清白的  - 是的
- I understand you were exonerated. - Yeah.
跟我来
Come with me.
Xgun擦枪小组 有偿招募译制成员 诚邀阁下
加入Q群：545053435
请注明职务：翻译、听译、aegisub特效（熟练手）
对字幕有任何意见和建议的同学请加Q群：544487177